<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hadir&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hadir&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://notes.hadir.ga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Material for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.hadir.ga/example/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful documentation Material is a theme for Hugo, a fast and flexible static site generator. It is built using Google&amp;rsquo;s material design guidelines, fully responsive, optimized for touch and pointer devices as well as all sorts of screen sizes.
Material is very lightweight – it is built from scratch using Javascript and CSS that weighs less than 30kb (minified, gzipped and excluding Google Fonts and Analytics). Yet, it is highly customizable and degrades gracefully in older browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>Install Guest Additions on Ubuntu  Click on Install Guest Additions… from the Devices menu, then choose to browse the content of the CD when requested. Check if sudo is installed, otherwise install it. bash su - password: apt-get install sudo -y usermod -aG sudo yourusername sudo apt-get install linux-headers-amd64 `  if it is not running, then install gcc :bash:&amp;lsquo;sudo apt-get install build-essential gcc make perl&amp;rsquo;
 Run :bash:&amp;ldquo;sudo sh /media/your_username/VBoxLinuxAdditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/add-new-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/add-new-repository/</guid>
      <description> Adding new repositories to add a new repository in ubuntu linux, it is necessary to run the terminal as root.
To run terminal as root, use:
sudo -i  Then run the command line on bash:
add-apt-repository &#39;deb uri distribution [component1] [component2] [...]&#39;  or
add-apt-repository ppa:&amp;lt;ppa_name&amp;gt;  Example
add-apt-repository &#39;deb http://apt.postgresql.org/pub/repos/apt/ bionic-pgdg main&#39; add-apt-repository ppa:postgresql  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/installation-files-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/installation-files-/</guid>
      <description>Installing &amp;lsquo;.sh&amp;rsquo; files  Make the file executable: Here we have two options: a) right click over the file, go to properties, then click on the Permissions tab and then in Execute, check the &amp;lsquo;Allow executing file as program&amp;rsquo; option. b) In the terminal write this command line chmod ug+x ./file_name.sh
 Execute the file in the terminal using the command line, ./file_name.sh
  Installing a &amp;lsquo;.deb&amp;rsquo; file  Execute in the terminal using the command line, sudo dpkg -i filename.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.hadir.ga/linux_ubuntu/postgresql/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL in Ubuntu Installation Ubuntu comands to install postgresql:
$ update the repository base  Install the repository:
$ sudo apt-get install postgresql-10  Setting the role user: The default postgresql user role is the postgres, then to activate it, type at bash console:
$ sudo -i -u postgres  So you can access to the prompt :bash:&amp;lsquo;$ psql&amp;rsquo;, or use the next command to access postgresql role without change bash role:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://notes.hadir.ga/python/anaconda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.hadir.ga/python/anaconda/</guid>
      <description>Create a virtual environment To create new python a virtual environment in an specific folder and with an specific python version:
.. code-block:: bash conda create -p ~/pyenvs/djenv35 python=3.5 or python to install the same version installed with conda
To create the environment into the default anaconda&amp;rsquo;s :bash:&amp;lsquo;env&amp;rsquo; folder
.. code-block:: bash conda create -n djenv35 python=3.5
to activate/deactivate it when create into a specific path folder, type on terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>